{
	"description": "Words for JLPT N5 which only use basic kanji",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "お兄さん", "answers": [ "おにいさん" ], "comment": "older brother; elder brother\n(vocative) young man; buddy; fella; laddie" },
	{ "question": "お姉さん", "answers": [ "おねえさん" ], "comment": "elder sister\n(vocative) young lady\nmiss (referring to a waitress, etc.)\nma'am (used by geisha to refer to their superiors)\nolder girl (no relation)" },
	{ "question": "お弁当", "answers": [ "おべんとう" ], "comment": "bento; Japanese box lunch" },
	{ "question": "お手洗い", "answers": [ "おてあらい" ], "comment": "toilet; restroom; lavatory; bathroom" },
	{ "question": "お母さん", "answers": [ "おかあさん" ], "comment": "mother" },
	{ "question": "お父さん", "answers": [ "おとうさん" ], "comment": "father; dad; papa; pa; pop; daddy; dada" },
	{ "question": "お皿", "answers": [ "おさら" ], "comment": "plate; dish" },
	{ "question": "お茶", "answers": [ "おちゃ" ], "comment": "tea (usu. green)\ntea break (at work)\ntea ceremony" },
	{ "question": "お酒", "answers": [ "おさけ" ], "comment": "alcohol; sake" },
	{ "question": "お金", "answers": [ "おかね" ], "comment": "money" },
	{ "question": "お風呂", "answers": [ "おふろ" ], "comment": "bath" },
	{ "question": "ご飯", "answers": [ "ごはん" ], "comment": "cooked rice\nmeal" },
	{ "question": "さ来年", "answers": [ "さらいねん" ], "comment": "year after next" },
	{ "question": "鳥肉", "answers": [ "とりにく" ], "comment": "chicken meat" },
	{ "question": "もう一度", "answers": [ "もういちど" ], "comment": "once more; again" },
	{ "question": "一", "answers": [ "いち" ], "comment": "one\nbest\nfirst; foremost\nbeginning; start\nbottom string (on a shamisen, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "一つ", "answers": [ "ひとつ" ], "comment": "one\nfor one thing\nonly\n(not) even\njust (e.g. \"just try it\")" },
	{ "question": "一人", "answers": [ "ひとり" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "一日", "answers": [ "ついたち", "いちにち", "いちじつ" ], "comment": "one day\nfirst day of the month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month" },
	{ "question": "一昨年", "answers": [ "おととし", "いっさくねん" ], "comment": "year before last" },
	{ "question": "一昨日", "answers": [ "おととい", "いっさくじつ" ], "comment": "day before yesterday" },
	{ "question": "一月", "answers": [ "ひとつき", "いちがつ" ], "comment": "January\none month" },
	{ "question": "一緒", "answers": [ "いっしょ" ], "comment": "together\nat the same time\nsame; identical" },
	{ "question": "七", "answers": [ "なな", "しち" ], "comment": "seven\nhepta-" },
	{ "question": "七つ", "answers": [ "ななつ" ], "comment": "seven" },
	{ "question": "七日", "answers": [ "なのか" ], "comment": "the seventh day of the month\nseven days" },
	{ "question": "万", "answers": [ "まん", "よろず" ], "comment": "many; all\n10,000; ten thousand\nmyriad\neverything; all\nvarious" },
	{ "question": "三", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "three\ntri-" },
	{ "question": "三つ", "answers": [ "みっつ" ], "comment": "three" },
	{ "question": "三日", "answers": [ "みっか" ], "comment": "the third day of the month\nthree days" },
	{ "question": "上", "answers": [ "うえ", "じょう", "かみ" ], "comment": "above; up; over; elder (e.g. daughter)\ntop; summit\nsurface; on\nbefore; previous\nsuperiority; one's superior (i.e. one's elder)\non top of that; besides; what's more\nupon (further inspection, etc.); based on (and occurring after)\nmatters concerning...; as concerns ...\nsince (i.e. \"for that reason\")\nupper; upward; outer; surface; top\nupper reaches (of a river); upper stream\ntop; upper part; upper half (of the body)\nlong ago\nbeginning; first\nperson of high rank (e.g. the emperor)\ngovernment; imperial court\nimperial capital (i.e. Kyoto); capital region (i.e. Kansai); region (or direction of) the imperial palace\nhead (of a table)\nwife; mistress (of a restaurant)\nfirst volume (e.g. book)" },
	{ "question": "上手", "answers": [ "じょうず", "うわて", "かみて" ], "comment": "skill; skillful; dexterity\nflattery\nupper part\nupper stream; upper course of a river\nright side of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage left (actor's POV)\nskillful (only in comparisons); dexterity (only in comparisons)\nover-arm grip on opponent's belt" },
	{ "question": "上着", "answers": [ "うわぎ" ], "comment": "coat; tunic; jacket; outer garment" },
	{ "question": "下", "answers": [ "した", "もと", "しも", "げ" ], "comment": "below; down; under; younger (e.g. daughter)\nbottom\nbeneath; underneath\njust after; right after\ninferiority; one's inferior (i.e. one's junior)\ntrade-in\npreliminary; preparatory\nunder (esp. influence or guidance)\nlowness (of degree, value, etc.); inferiority\nsecond volume (of two); third volume (of three)\nlower reaches (of a river)\nbottom; lower part\nlower half (of the body, esp. the privates); feces (faeces); urine; menses\nend; far from the imperial palace (i.e. far from Kyoto, esp. of western Japan)\ndirty (e.g. dirty jokes, etc.)\nunder (being in said condition or environment)" },
	{ "question": "下手", "answers": [ "へた", "したて", "しもて" ], "comment": "humble position; inferior\nunderarm grip on opponent's belt\nlower part; foot; lower direction\nleft part of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage right (actor's POV)\nunskillful; poor; awkward\nimprudent; untactful" },
	{ "question": "両親", "answers": [ "りょうしん" ], "comment": "parents; both parents" },
	{ "question": "並ぶ", "answers": [ "ならぶ" ], "comment": "to line up; to stand in a line\nto rival; to match; to equal" },
	{ "question": "並べる", "answers": [ "ならべる" ], "comment": "to line up; to set up; to arrange in a line\nto enumerate; to itemize\nto be equal (to); to compare well (with); to be as good (as)" },
	{ "question": "中", "answers": [ "なか", "ちゅう" ], "comment": "inside; in\namong; within\ncenter (centre); middle\nduring; while\ninside; within\nwhile\namong; amongst; between\nwe (referring to one's in-group, e.g. company, etc.); our\nmy spouse\nimperial palace grounds\nemperor\nI (primarily used by women and children); me\nmedium; average; middle\nmoderation\nmiddle school\nChina\nvolume two (of three)\nduring (a certain time when one did or is doing something); under (construction, etc.); while\nin; out of (e.g. three out of ten people)\nthrough; throughout; in the course of\nall over or throughout (e.g. a place)\nred dragon tile\nwinning hand with a pung (or kong) of red dragon tiles" },
	{ "question": "乗る", "answers": [ "のる" ], "comment": "to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.); to get in; to board; to take; to embark\nto get on (e.g. a footstool); to step on; to jump on; to sit on; to mount\nto reach; to go over; to pass\nto follow; to stay (on track); to go with (the times, etc.)\nto take part; to participate; to join\nto get into the swing (and sing, dance, etc.)\nto be deceived; to be taken in\nto be carried; to be spread; to be scattered\nto stick; to attach; to take; to go on" },
	{ "question": "九", "answers": [ "きゅう", "く" ], "comment": "nine" },
	{ "question": "九つ", "answers": [ "ここのつ" ], "comment": "nine" },
	{ "question": "九日", "answers": [ "ここのか" ], "comment": "the ninth day of the month\nnine days" },
	{ "question": "二", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "two" },
	{ "question": "二つ", "answers": [ "ふたつ" ], "comment": "two" },
	{ "question": "二人", "answers": [ "ふたり" ], "comment": "two persons; two people; pair; couple" },
	{ "question": "二十日", "answers": [ "はつか" ], "comment": "twentieth day of the month\ntwenty days" },
	{ "question": "二十歳", "answers": [ "はたち" ], "comment": "20 years old\ntwenty years" },
	{ "question": "二日", "answers": [ "ふつか" ], "comment": "second day of the month\ntwo days" },
	{ "question": "五", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "five" },
	{ "question": "五つ", "answers": [ "いつつ" ], "comment": "five" },
	{ "question": "五日", "answers": [ "いつか" ], "comment": "the fifth day of the month\nfive days" },
	{ "question": "交差点", "answers": [ "こうさてん" ], "comment": "crossing; intersection" },
	{ "question": "交番", "answers": [ "こうばん" ], "comment": "police box; small neighborhood police station\nalternation; alternating (e.g. current)" },
	{ "question": "人", "answers": [ "ひと" ], "comment": "man; person\nhuman being; mankind; people\nhuman (Homo sapiens); humans as a species\ncharacter; personality\nman of talent; true man\nanother person; other people; others\nadult" },
	{ "question": "今", "answers": [ "いま" ], "comment": "now; the present time; just now; soon; immediately; (one) more" },
	{ "question": "今年", "answers": [ "ことし" ], "comment": "this year" },
	{ "question": "今日", "answers": [ "きょう", "こんにち" ], "comment": "today; this day\nthese days; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "今晩", "answers": [ "こんばん" ], "comment": "tonight; this evening" },
	{ "question": "今月", "answers": [ "こんげつ" ], "comment": "this month" },
	{ "question": "今朝", "answers": [ "けさ" ], "comment": "this morning" },
	{ "question": "今週", "answers": [ "こんしゅう" ], "comment": "this week" },
	{ "question": "仕事", "answers": [ "しごと" ], "comment": "work; job; business; occupation; employment; vocation; task\nwork" },
	{ "question": "休み", "answers": [ "やすみ" ], "comment": "rest; recess; respite\nvacation; holiday; absence; suspension\ndormancy (of a silkworm prior to moulting)" },
	{ "question": "休む", "answers": [ "やすむ" ], "comment": "to be absent; to take a day off\nto rest; to have a break\nto go to bed; to (lie down to) sleep; to turn in; to retire\nto stop doing some ongoing activity for a time; to suspend business" },
	{ "question": "会社", "answers": [ "かいしゃ" ], "comment": "company; corporation\nworkplace" },
	{ "question": "低い", "answers": [ "ひくい" ], "comment": "low (rank, degree, value, content, quality, etc.)\nlow (position); close to the ground\nshort (height)\ndeep (voice); in a low key; low (volume)" },
	{ "question": "住む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to live (of humans); to reside; to inhabit; to dwell; to abide" },
	{ "question": "体", "answers": [ "からだ", "てい" ], "comment": "body\ntorso; trunk\nbuild; physique; constitution\nhealth\ncorpse; dead body\nbody; physique; posture\nshape; form; style\nsubstance; identity; reality\nfield\ncounter for humanoid forms (e.g. dolls, statues, corpses, etc.)\ntypeface; type\nappearance; air; condition; state; form" },
	{ "question": "何", "answers": [ "なに", "なん" ], "comment": "what\nhow many\nyou-know-what; that\nwhatsit; what's the expression; what do you call them\nwhat?\nhey!" },
	{ "question": "作る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "作文", "answers": [ "さくぶん" ], "comment": "writing (an essay, prose, etc.); composition\nformal writing with little real meaning\nwriting (poetry); composing" },
	{ "question": "使う", "answers": [ "つかう" ], "comment": "to use (a thing, method, etc.); to make use of; to put to use\nto use (a person, animal, puppet, etc.); to employ; to handle; to manage; to manipulate\nto use (time, money, etc.); to spend; to consume\nto use (language); to speak" },
	{ "question": "便利", "answers": [ "べんり" ], "comment": "convenient; handy; useful" },
	{ "question": "借りる", "answers": [ "かりる" ], "comment": "to borrow; to have a loan\nto rent; to hire" },
	{ "question": "働く", "answers": [ "はたらく" ], "comment": "to work; to labor; to labour\nto function; to operate; to be effective; to work (i.e. ... works); to come into play\nto commit (e.g. a crime); to perpetrate; to do; to act; to practise; to practice\nto be conjugated" },
	{ "question": "元気", "answers": [ "げんき" ], "comment": "lively; full of spirit; energetic; vigorous; vital; spirited\nhealthy; well; fit; in good health" },
	{ "question": "兄", "answers": [ "あに" ], "comment": "elder brother; older brother" },
	{ "question": "兄弟", "answers": [ "きょうだい" ], "comment": "siblings; brothers and sisters\nbrothers\nsiblings-in-law; brothers-in-law; sisters-in-law\nmate; friend" },
	{ "question": "先", "answers": [ "さき", "せん" ], "comment": "previous; prior; former; first; earlier; some time ago; preceding\npoint (e.g. pencil); tip; end; nozzle\nhead (of a line); front\nahead; the other side\nthe future; hereafter\ndestination\nthe other party\nformer; previous; old\nfirst move (in go, shogi, etc.); opening move" },
	{ "question": "先月", "answers": [ "せんげつ" ], "comment": "last month" },
	{ "question": "先生", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "teacher; master; doctor\nwith names of teachers, etc. as an honorific\nprevious existence\nboy" },
	{ "question": "先週", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "last week; the week before" },
	{ "question": "入る", "answers": [ "はいる", "いる" ], "comment": "to get in; to go in; to come in; to flow into; to set; to set in\nto enter; to go into\nto break into\nto join; to enroll\nto contain; to hold; to accommodate\nto have (an income of)\nto get; to receive; to score" },
	{ "question": "入れる", "answers": [ "いれる" ], "comment": "to put in; to let in; to take in; to bring in; to insert; to set (a jewel, etc.); to ink in (e.g. a tattoo)\nto admit; to accept; to employ; to hire\nto accept; to comply; to grant; to adopt (a policy, etc.); to take (advice, etc.); to listen to; to pay attention to\nto include\nto pay (one's rent, etc.)\nto cast (a vote)\nto make (tea, coffee, etc.)\nto turn on (a switch, etc.)\nto send (a fax); to call" },
	{ "question": "入口", "answers": [ "いりぐち" ], "comment": "entrance; entry; gate; approach; mouth" },
	{ "question": "全部", "answers": [ "ぜんぶ" ], "comment": "all; entire; whole; altogether" },
	{ "question": "八", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "eight" },
	{ "question": "八つ", "answers": [ "やっつ" ], "comment": "eight" },
	{ "question": "八日", "answers": [ "ようか" ], "comment": "the eighth day of the month\neight days" },
	{ "question": "公園", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "(public) park" },
	{ "question": "六", "answers": [ "ろく" ], "comment": "six" },
	{ "question": "六つ", "answers": [ "むっつ" ], "comment": "six" },
	{ "question": "六日", "answers": [ "むいか" ], "comment": "sixth day of the month\nsix days" },
	{ "question": "円", "answers": [ "えん", "まる" ], "comment": "yen; Japanese monetary unit\ncircle\ncircle\nentirety; whole; full; complete\nmoney; dough; moola\nenclosure inside a castle's walls\nsoft-shelled turtle\nsuffix for ship names; suffix for names of people (esp. infants); suffix for names of swords, armour, musical instruments, etc.; suffix for names of dogs, horses, etc." },
	{ "question": "写真", "answers": [ "しゃしん" ], "comment": "photograph; photo; picture; snapshot; snap\nmovie" },
	{ "question": "冬", "answers": [ "ふゆ" ], "comment": "winter" },
	{ "question": "出かける", "answers": [ "でかける" ], "comment": "to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing); to leave; to depart; to start; to set out\nto be about to leave; to be just going out" },
	{ "question": "出す", "answers": [ "だす" ], "comment": "to take out; to get out\nto put out; to reveal; to show\nto submit (e.g. thesis); to turn in\nto publish; to make public\nto send (e.g. letter)\nto produce (a sound); to start (fire)\nto serve (food)\nto begin ...; to start to ...; to burst into ..." },
	{ "question": "出る", "answers": [ "でる" ], "comment": "to leave; to exit; to go out; to come out; to get out\nto leave (on a journey); to depart; to start out; to set out\nto move forward\nto come to; to get to; to lead to; to reach\nto appear; to come out; to emerge; to surface; to come forth; to turn up; to be found; to be detected; to be discovered; to be exposed; to show; to be exhibited; to be on display\nto appear (in print); to be published; to be announced; to be issued; to be listed; to come out\nto attend; to participate; to take part; to enter (an event); to play in; to perform\nto be stated; to be expressed; to come up; to be brought up; to be raised\nto sell\nto exceed; to go over\nto stick out; to protrude\nto break out; to occur; to start; to originate\nto be produced\nto come from; to be derived from\nto be given; to get; to receive; to be offered; to be provided; to be presented; to be submitted; to be handed in; to be turned in; to be paid\nto answer (phone, door, etc.); to get\nto assume (an attitude); to act; to behave\nto pick up (speed, etc.); to gain\nto flow (e.g. tears); to run; to bleed\nto graduate" },
	{ "question": "出口", "answers": [ "でぐち" ], "comment": "exit; gateway; way out; outlet; leak; vent" },
	{ "question": "分かる", "answers": [ "わかる" ], "comment": "to understand; to comprehend; to grasp; to see; to get; to follow\nto become clear; to be known; to be discovered; to be realized; to be realised; to be found out" },
	{ "question": "切る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "to cut; to cut through; to perform (surgery)\nto sever (connections, ties)\nto turn off (e.g. the light)\nto terminate (e.g. a conversation); to hang up (the phone); to disconnect\nto punch (a ticket); to tear off (a stub)\nto open (something sealed)\nto start\nto set (a limit); to do (something) in less or within a certain time; to issue (stamps, vouchers, etc.)\nto reduce; to decrease; to discount\nto shake off (water, etc.); to let drip-dry; to let drain\nto cross; to traverse\nto criticize sharply\nto act decisively; to do (something noticeable); to go first; to make (certain facial expressions, in kabuki)\nto turn (a vehicle)\nto curl (a ball); to bend; to cut\nto shuffle (cards)\nto dismiss; to sack; to let go; to expulse; to excommunicate\nto dig (a groove); to cut (a stencil, on a mimeograph)\nto trump\nto cut (the connection between two groups) (in go)\nto start a fire (with wood-wood friction or by striking a metal against stone)\nto draw (a shape) in the air (with a sword, etc.)\nto finish; to complete" },
	{ "question": "切手", "answers": [ "きって" ], "comment": "stamp (postage); merchandise certificate\nman of ability" },
	{ "question": "初めて", "answers": [ "はじめて" ], "comment": "for the first time\nonly after ... is it ...; only when ... do you ..." },
	{ "question": "前", "answers": [ "まえ" ], "comment": "ago; before (some event); previously; (minutes) to (the hour)\nin front (of); before (e.g. the house)\nhead (of a line); front (e.g. of a bus); fore part\nin the presence of\nhelping; portion\nprivates; private parts" },
	{ "question": "動物", "answers": [ "どうぶつ" ], "comment": "animal" },
	{ "question": "北", "answers": [ "きた" ], "comment": "north\nthe North; northern territories\nNorth Korea\nnorth wind" },
	{ "question": "医者", "answers": [ "いしゃ" ], "comment": "(medical) doctor; physician" },
	{ "question": "十", "answers": [ "じゅう", "とお" ], "comment": "ten" },
	{ "question": "十日", "answers": [ "とおか" ], "comment": "the tenth day of the month\nten days" },
	{ "question": "千", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "1,000; thousand" },
	{ "question": "午前", "answers": [ "ごぜん" ], "comment": "morning; a.m." },
	{ "question": "午後", "answers": [ "ごご" ], "comment": "afternoon; p.m." },
	{ "question": "半", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "half; semi-\nhalf-past\nodd number\nunit of land area (595.8 m^2)" },
	{ "question": "半分", "answers": [ "はんぶん" ], "comment": "half\nhalf minute" },
	{ "question": "南", "answers": [ "みなみ" ], "comment": "south" },
	{ "question": "去年", "answers": [ "きょねん" ], "comment": "last year" },
	{ "question": "友達", "answers": [ "ともだち" ], "comment": "friend; companion" },
	{ "question": "取る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take; to pick up; to harvest; to earn; to win; to choose\nto steal\nto eat; to have (a meal)\nto remove (one's glasses, etc.)\nto compete (in sumo, cards, etc.); to play" },
	{ "question": "口", "answers": [ "くち" ], "comment": "mouth\nopening; hole; gap; orifice\nmouth (of a bottle); spout; nozzle; mouthpiece\ngate; door; entrance; exit\nspeaking; speech; talk (i.e. gossip)\ntaste; palate\nmouth (to feed)\nopening (i.e. vacancy); available position\ninvitation; summons\nkind; sort; type\nopening (i.e. beginning)\ncounter for mouthfuls, shares (of money), and swords\nmouth; speech\ncounter for people or implements" },
	{ "question": "古い", "answers": [ "ふるい" ], "comment": "old (not person); aged; ancient; antiquated; stale; threadbare; outmoded; obsolete article" },
	{ "question": "台所", "answers": [ "だいどころ" ], "comment": "kitchen\nfinancial situation" },
	{ "question": "右", "answers": [ "みぎ" ], "comment": "right; right hand side\nafore-mentioned (esp. in vertical Japanese writing); foregoing; forgoing; above" },
	{ "question": "同じ", "answers": [ "おなじ" ], "comment": "same; identical; equal; uniform; equivalent; similar; common (origin); changeless; alike\n(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway; anyhow; in either case" },
	{ "question": "名前", "answers": [ "なまえ" ], "comment": "name; full name\ngiven name; first name" },
	{ "question": "向こう", "answers": [ "むこう" ], "comment": "opposite side; other side; opposite direction\nover there; that way; far away; beyond\nthe other party; the other person\nfuture (starting now)" },
	{ "question": "呼ぶ", "answers": [ "よぶ" ], "comment": "to call out (to); to call; to invoke\nto summon (a doctor, etc.)\nto invite\nto designate; to name; to brand\nto garner (support, etc.); to gather\nto take as one's wife" },
	{ "question": "問題", "answers": [ "もんだい" ], "comment": "question (e.g. on a test); problem\nproblem (e.g. societal, political); question; issue; subject (e.g. of research); case; matter\nquestion (i.e. doubt)\npublic discussion; controversy\ntrouble; problem; inconvenience; difficulty" },
	{ "question": "四", "answers": [ "よん", "し" ], "comment": "four" },
	{ "question": "四つ", "answers": [ "よっつ" ], "comment": "four" },
	{ "question": "四日", "answers": [ "よっか" ], "comment": "fourth day of the month\nfour days" },
	{ "question": "国", "answers": [ "くに" ], "comment": "country; state\nregion\nnational government; central government\nhome (i.e. hometown, home country)\nprovince (of Japan)\nland; earth" },
	{ "question": "土", "answers": [ "つち", "ど" ], "comment": "earth; soil; dirt; clay; mud\nthe earth (historically, esp. as opposed to the heavens); the ground; the land\nlow-quality torinoko-gami (containing mud)\nSaturday\nearth (third of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "土曜日", "answers": [ "どようび" ], "comment": "Saturday" },
	{ "question": "地図", "answers": [ "ちず" ], "comment": "map" },
	{ "question": "売る", "answers": [ "うる" ], "comment": "to sell" },
	{ "question": "夏", "answers": [ "なつ" ], "comment": "summer" },
	{ "question": "夏休み", "answers": [ "なつやすみ" ], "comment": "summer vacation; summer holiday" },
	{ "question": "夕方", "answers": [ "ゆうがた" ], "comment": "evening; dusk" },
	{ "question": "夕飯", "answers": [ "ゆうはん" ], "comment": "evening meal" },
	{ "question": "外", "answers": [ "そと", "ほか" ], "comment": "outside; exterior\nopen air\nother place\nother (place, thing, person); the rest\noutside; beyond\nnothing except; nothing but; nothing apart from; nothing aside from; no choice (but to)\nbesides...; in addition to...\nanother place; somewhere else; strange parts\noutside (one's family or group); those people\nunrelated matter\noutside of; not covered by" },
	{ "question": "外国", "answers": [ "がいこく" ], "comment": "foreign country" },
	{ "question": "外国人", "answers": [ "がいこくじん" ], "comment": "foreigner; foreign citizen; foreign national; alien; non-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "多い", "answers": [ "おおい" ], "comment": "many; numerous; a lot\nlarge quantity; large amount\nfrequent; common" },
	{ "question": "夜", "answers": [ "よる", "よ" ], "comment": "evening; night" },
	{ "question": "大きい", "answers": [ "おおきい" ], "comment": "big; large; great; loud" },
	{ "question": "大きな", "answers": [ "おおきな" ], "comment": "big; large; great" },
	{ "question": "大丈夫", "answers": [ "だいじょうぶ" ], "comment": "safe; all right; alright; OK; okay; sure\ncertainly; surely; undoubtedly\ngreat man; fine figure of a man\ngreat man; fine figure of a man" },
	{ "question": "大人", "answers": [ "おとな" ], "comment": "adult\nman of substance or virtue; gentleman\ngiant\nadult" },
	{ "question": "大使館", "answers": [ "たいしかん" ], "comment": "embassy" },
	{ "question": "大切", "answers": [ "たいせつ" ], "comment": "important; necessary; indispensable\nbeloved; precious; dear; cherished; valuable\ncareful\nlarge cut (e.g. of meat)\nlast piece of the day's programme; last act of a play; comic dialogue as the last item in vaudeville, music hall, etc." },
	{ "question": "大好き", "answers": [ "だいすき" ], "comment": "loveable; very likeable; like very much" },
	{ "question": "大学", "answers": [ "だいがく" ], "comment": "post-secondary education institution, incl. university, college, etc.\nformer central university of Kyoto (established under the ritsuryo system for the training of government administrators)\nthe Great Learning (one of the Four Books)" },
	{ "question": "天気", "answers": [ "てんき" ], "comment": "weather; the elements\nfair weather; fine weather" },
	{ "question": "太い", "answers": [ "ふとい" ], "comment": "fat; thick\ndeep (of a voice)\ndaring; shameless; brazen\nlucky (billiards)" },
	{ "question": "奥さん", "answers": [ "おくさん" ], "comment": "wife; your wife; his wife; married lady; madam" },
	{ "question": "女", "answers": [ "おんな", "め" ], "comment": "female; woman; female sex\nfemale lover; girlfriend; mistress; (someone's) woman\nwife" },
	{ "question": "女の子", "answers": [ "おんなのこ" ], "comment": "girl; daughter\nyoung woman\nwoman; girl" },
	{ "question": "好き", "answers": [ "すき" ], "comment": "liking; fondness; love" },
	{ "question": "妹", "answers": [ "いもうと" ], "comment": "younger sister\ndarling (only of a woman); dear; honey; my betrothed\none's sister\nfriend" },
	{ "question": "姉", "answers": [ "あね" ], "comment": "older sister; elder sister" },
	{ "question": "始まる", "answers": [ "はじまる" ], "comment": "to begin; to start; to commence\nto happen (again); to begin (anew)\nto date (from); to originate (in)" },
	{ "question": "子", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "child\nyoung (animal)\nyoung woman; young geisha\noffshoot\ninterest\nnew shares\nplayer who is not a dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "子供", "answers": [ "こども" ], "comment": "child; children" },
	{ "question": "学校", "answers": [ "がっこう" ], "comment": "school" },
	{ "question": "学生", "answers": [ "がくせい" ], "comment": "student (esp. a university student)\nHeian-period student of government administration\nBuddhist scholar; researcher at a Buddhist temple; person studying Buddhism\nlearning; scholarship" },
	{ "question": "安い", "answers": [ "やすい" ], "comment": "cheap; inexpensive\ncalm; peaceful; quiet" },
	{ "question": "家", "answers": [ "いえ", "うち" ], "comment": "house; residence; dwelling\nfamily; household\nlineage; family name\nhouse; home (one's own)\n(one's) family; (one's) household" },
	{ "question": "家庭", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "home; family; household" },
	{ "question": "家族", "answers": [ "かぞく" ], "comment": "family; members of a family" },
	{ "question": "宿題", "answers": [ "しゅくだい" ], "comment": "homework" },
	{ "question": "寒い", "answers": [ "さむい" ], "comment": "cold (e.g. weather)\nuninteresting (esp. joke); lame; dull; weak; corny" },
	{ "question": "寝る", "answers": [ "ねる" ], "comment": "to lie down\nto go to bed; to lie in bed\nto sleep (lying down)\nto sleep (with someone, i.e. have intercourse)\nto lie idle" },
	{ "question": "小さい", "answers": [ "ちいさい" ], "comment": "small; little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "小さな", "answers": [ "ちいさな" ], "comment": "small; little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "少し", "answers": [ "すこし" ], "comment": "small quantity; little; few; something\nlittle while\nshort distance" },
	{ "question": "少ない", "answers": [ "すくない" ], "comment": "few; a little; scarce; insufficient; seldom" },
	{ "question": "山", "answers": [ "やま" ], "comment": "mountain; hill\nmine (e.g. coal mine)\nheap; pile\ncrown (of a hat); thread (of a screw); tread (of a tire); protruding part of an object\nclimax; peak; critical point\nguess; speculation\ncriminal case; crime\nmountain climbing; mountaineering\nfestival float (esp. one mounted with a decorative halberd)\nwall; wall tile\ntemple; temple grounds\nwild" },
	{ "question": "川", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "river; stream\nthe .... river; (suffix used with the names of rivers)" },
	{ "question": "左", "answers": [ "ひだり", "さ" ], "comment": "left; left hand side\nleft (esp. in vertical Japanese writing); the following" },
	{ "question": "帰る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to return; to come home; to go home; to go back\nto leave\nto get home; to get to home plate" },
	{ "question": "年", "answers": [ "とし", "ねん" ], "comment": "year\nage; years\npast one's prime; old age\nyear (e.g. AD)\ncounter for years" },
	{ "question": "広い", "answers": [ "ひろい" ], "comment": "spacious; vast; wide" },
	{ "question": "店", "answers": [ "みせ" ], "comment": "store; shop; establishment; restaurant" },
	{ "question": "建物", "answers": [ "たてもの" ], "comment": "building" },
	{ "question": "引く", "answers": [ "ひく" ], "comment": "to pull\nto draw (attention, etc.); to attract (interest, etc.)\nto draw back\nto draw (card, mahjong tile, etc.)\nto draw (plan, line, etc.)\nto catch (cold)\nto play (string instr.)\nto look up (e.g. dictionary); to consult\nto haul; to pull (vehicles)\nto subtract\nto ebb; to fade\nto descend (from); to inherit (a characteristic)\nto quote; to raise (as evidence)\nto lay (a cable); to draw (a cable)" },
	{ "question": "弟", "answers": [ "おとうと" ], "comment": "younger brother; little brother; kid brother\npupil; apprentice" },
	{ "question": "弱い", "answers": [ "よわい" ], "comment": "weak; frail; delicate; tender; unskilled; weak (wine)" },
	{ "question": "強い", "answers": [ "つよい" ], "comment": "strong; powerful; mighty; potent\nresistant; resilient; durable\ntough; stiff; hard\ninflexible; obstinate; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "待つ", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "to wait\nto await; to look forward to; to anticipate\nto depend on; to need" },
	{ "question": "後", "answers": [ "あと", "のち", "ご" ], "comment": "behind; rear\nafter; later\nafter one's death\nremainder; the rest\ndescendant; successor; heir\nmore (e.g. five more minutes); left\nalso; in addition\npast; previous\nlater; afterwards; since\nfuture\nafter one's death\ndescendant\nback; behind; rear\nbuttocks; behind; rump; bottom\nundersurface; bottom\nlast place; end\nconsequence\nafter" },
	{ "question": "後ろ", "answers": [ "うしろ" ], "comment": "back; behind; rear" },
	{ "question": "忘れる", "answers": [ "わすれる" ], "comment": "to forget; to leave carelessly; to be forgetful of; to forget about; to forget (an article)" },
	{ "question": "忙しい", "answers": [ "いそがしい" ], "comment": "busy; occupied; hectic\nrestless; hurried; fidgety" },
	{ "question": "悪い", "answers": [ "わるい" ], "comment": "bad; poor; inferior\nevil; sinful\nunprofitable; unbeneficial\nat fault; to blame; in the wrong\nsorry\nhateful; abominable; poor-looking; detestable\namazing; fantastic; admirable; lovely; wonderful\ndifficult to ...; hard to ..." },
	{ "question": "意味", "answers": [ "いみ" ], "comment": "meaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "所", "answers": [ "ところ" ], "comment": "place; spot; scene; site\naddress\ndistrict; area; locality\none's house\npoint; aspect; side; facet\npassage (in text); part\nspace; room\nthing; matter\nwhereupon; as a result\nabout to; on the verge of\nwas just doing; was in the process of doing; have just done; just finished doing\ncounter for places" },
	{ "question": "手", "answers": [ "て" ], "comment": "hand; arm\nforepaw; foreleg\nhandle\nhand; worker; help\ntrouble; care; effort\nmeans; way; trick; move; technique; workmanship\nhand; handwriting\nkind; type; sort\none's hands; one's possession\nability to cope\nhand (of cards)\ndirection\nmove (in go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "手紙", "answers": [ "てがみ" ], "comment": "letter" },
	{ "question": "押す", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "to push; to press\nto apply pressure from above; to press down\nto stamp (i.e. a passport); to apply a seal\nto affix (e.g. gold leaf)\nto press (someone for something); to urge; to compel; to influence\nto overwhelm; to overpower; to repress\nto push (events along); to advance (a plan)\nto do in spite of ...; to do even though ...; to force\nto make sure\nto be pressed for time\nto advance troops; to attack\n(of light) to be diffused across an entire surface" },
	{ "question": "持つ", "answers": [ "もつ" ], "comment": "to hold (in one's hand); to take; to carry\nto possess; to have; to own\nto maintain; to keep\nto last; to be durable; to keep; to survive\nto take charge of; to be in charge of" },
	{ "question": "教える", "answers": [ "おしえる" ], "comment": "to teach; to instruct\nto tell; to inform\nto preach" },
	{ "question": "教室", "answers": [ "きょうしつ" ], "comment": "classroom\ndepartment; laboratory\nsingle-room school; small school" },
	{ "question": "散歩", "answers": [ "さんぽ" ], "comment": "walk; stroll" },
	{ "question": "文章", "answers": [ "ぶんしょう" ], "comment": "sentence; article; composition\n(writing) style" },
	{ "question": "料理", "answers": [ "りょうり" ], "comment": "cooking; cookery; cuisine\ndealing with something; handling; administration; management" },
	{ "question": "新しい", "answers": [ "あたらしい" ], "comment": "new; novel; fresh; recent; latest; up-to-date; modern" },
	{ "question": "新聞", "answers": [ "しんぶん" ], "comment": "newspaper" },
	{ "question": "方", "answers": [ "かた", "ほう" ], "comment": "direction; way\nperson; lady; gentleman\nmethod of; manner of; way of\ncare of ..\nperson in charge of ..\nside (e.g. \"on my mother's side\")\ndirection; way; side; area (in a particular direction)\nside (of an argument, etc.); one's part\ntype; category\nfield (of study, etc.)\nindicates one side of a comparison\nway; method; manner; means\nlength (of each side of a square)" },
	{ "question": "旅行", "answers": [ "りょこう" ], "comment": "travel; trip" },
	{ "question": "日曜日", "answers": [ "にちようび" ], "comment": "Sunday" },
	{ "question": "早い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; hasty; brisk\nearly (in the day, etc.); premature\n(too) soon; not yet; (too) early\neasy; simple; quick" },
	{ "question": "映画", "answers": [ "えいが" ], "comment": "movie; film" },
	{ "question": "映画館", "answers": [ "えいがかん" ], "comment": "movie theatre; movie theater; cinema" },
	{ "question": "春", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "spring; springtime\nNew Year\nprime (of one's life, etc.)\nadolescence; puberty\nsexuality" },
	{ "question": "昨夜", "answers": [ "さくや", "ゆうべ" ], "comment": "last night" },
	{ "question": "昨日", "answers": [ "きのう" ], "comment": "yesterday" },
	{ "question": "昼", "answers": [ "ひる" ], "comment": "noon; midday\ndaytime\nlunch" },
	{ "question": "昼ご飯", "answers": [ "ひるごはん" ], "comment": "lunch; midday meal" },
	{ "question": "時", "answers": [ "とき" ], "comment": "time; hour; moment\noccasion; case\nchance; opportunity; season\nthe times; the age; the day\ntense" },
	{ "question": "時々", "answers": [ "ときどき" ], "comment": "sometimes; at times" },
	{ "question": "時計", "answers": [ "とけい" ], "comment": "watch; clock; timepiece" },
	{ "question": "時間", "answers": [ "じかん" ], "comment": "time\nhours (period of)" },
	{ "question": "晩", "answers": [ "ばん" ], "comment": "evening\ncounter for nights" },
	{ "question": "晩ご飯", "answers": [ "ばんごはん" ], "comment": "dinner; evening meal" },
	{ "question": "晴れ", "answers": [ "はれ" ], "comment": "clear weather; fine weather\nformal; ceremonial; public\ncleared of suspicion" },
	{ "question": "晴れる", "answers": [ "はれる" ], "comment": "to clear up; to clear away; to be sunny; to stop raining\nto refresh (e.g. spirits)\nto be cleared (e.g. of a suspicion)\nto be dispelled; to be banished" },
	{ "question": "暗い", "answers": [ "くらい" ], "comment": "dark; gloomy\ndark (in colour); dull\ndepressed; dispirited\nsorrowful; bitter (as in a dark past)\nunclear; unfamiliar; unknown" },
	{ "question": "曲がる", "answers": [ "まがる" ], "comment": "to bend; to curve; to warp; to wind; to twist\nto turn\nto be awry; to be askew; to be crooked" },
	{ "question": "書く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "to write; to compose; to pen\nto draw; to paint" },
	{ "question": "月", "answers": [ "つき", "げつ" ], "comment": "moon\nmonth\nmonth (of the year); used after number or question word (e.g. nan or nani)\nMonday" },
	{ "question": "月曜日", "answers": [ "げつようび" ], "comment": "Monday" },
	{ "question": "有名", "answers": [ "ゆうめい" ], "comment": "famous\nfame" },
	{ "question": "服", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "clothes (esp. Western clothes)\ncounter for doses of medicine, gulps of tea, drags of a cigarette, etc." },
	{ "question": "木", "answers": [ "き", "もく" ], "comment": "tree; shrub; bush\nwood; timber\nThursday\nwood (first of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "木曜日", "answers": [ "もくようび" ], "comment": "Thursday" },
	{ "question": "本", "answers": [ "ほん", "もと" ], "comment": "book; volume; script\nthis; present\nmain; head\nreal; regular\ncounter for long cylindrical things\nbase; basis; foundation; root" },
	{ "question": "村", "answers": [ "むら" ], "comment": "village" },
	{ "question": "来る", "answers": [ "くる", "きたる" ], "comment": "to come (spatially or temporally); to approach; to arrive\nto come back; to do ... and come back\nto come to be; to become; to get; to grow; to continue\nto come from; to be caused by; to derive from\nto come to (i.e. \"when it comes to spinach ...\")\nnext (e.g. \"next April\"); forthcoming; coming\nto come; to arrive; to be due to" },
	{ "question": "来年", "answers": [ "らいねん" ], "comment": "next year" },
	{ "question": "来月", "answers": [ "らいげつ" ], "comment": "next month" },
	{ "question": "来週", "answers": [ "らいしゅう" ], "comment": "next week" },
	{ "question": "東", "answers": [ "ひがし", "あずま" ], "comment": "east" },
	{ "question": "果物", "answers": [ "くだもの" ], "comment": "fruit" },
	{ "question": "楽しい", "answers": [ "たのしい" ], "comment": "enjoyable; fun" },
	{ "question": "次", "answers": [ "つぎ" ], "comment": "next; following; subsequent\nstage; station" },
	{ "question": "欲しい", "answers": [ "ほしい" ], "comment": "wanted; wished for; in need of; desired\nI want (you) to" },
	{ "question": "歌", "answers": [ "うた" ], "comment": "song\nclassical Japanese poetry (esp. tanka)\nmodern poetry" },
	{ "question": "歌う", "answers": [ "うたう" ], "comment": "to sing\nto sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.); to compose a poem; to recite a poem" },
	{ "question": "止まる", "answers": [ "とまる" ], "comment": "to stop (moving); to come to a stop\nto stop (doing, working, being supplied); to come to a halt; to cease; to be stopped; to be suspended\nto alight; to perch on\nto remain; to abide; to stay (in the one place)\nto be limited to; to be confined to\nto cease; to stop; to be over" },
	{ "question": "歩く", "answers": [ "あるく" ], "comment": "to walk" },
	{ "question": "死ぬ", "answers": [ "しぬ" ], "comment": "to die; to pass away\nto lose spirit; to lose vigor; to look dead\nto cease; to stop" },
	{ "question": "母", "answers": [ "はは" ], "comment": "mother" },
	{ "question": "毎日", "answers": [ "まいにち" ], "comment": "every day" },
	{ "question": "毎晩", "answers": [ "まいばん" ], "comment": "every night" },
	{ "question": "毎朝", "answers": [ "まいあさ" ], "comment": "every morning" },
	{ "question": "毎週", "answers": [ "まいしゅう" ], "comment": "every week" },
	{ "question": "水", "answers": [ "みず", "すい" ], "comment": "water (esp. cool, fresh water, e.g. drinking water)\nfluid (esp. in an animal tissue); liquid\nflood; floodwaters\nwater offered to wrestlers just prior to a bout\nbreak granted to wrestlers engaged in a prolonged bout\nWednesday\nshaved ice (served with flavored syrup)\nwater (fifth of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "水曜日", "answers": [ "すいようび" ], "comment": "Wednesday" },
	{ "question": "洋服", "answers": [ "ようふく" ], "comment": "Western-style clothes (cf traditional Japanese clothes)" },
	{ "question": "洗う", "answers": [ "あらう" ], "comment": "to wash; to cleanse; to rinse\nto inquire into; investigate\nto purify (one's heart)\nto lave (e.g. shore); to wash over (e.g. deck); to sweep" },
	{ "question": "海", "answers": [ "うみ" ], "comment": "sea; ocean; waters" },
	{ "question": "消える", "answers": [ "きえる" ], "comment": "to go out; to vanish; to disappear" },
	{ "question": "消す", "answers": [ "けす" ], "comment": "to erase; to delete; to cross out\nto turn off power\nto extinguish; to put out\nto bump off" },
	{ "question": "漢字", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "Chinese characters; kanji" },
	{ "question": "火", "answers": [ "ひ", "か" ], "comment": "fire; flame; blaze\nTuesday\nfire (second of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "火曜日", "answers": [ "かようび" ], "comment": "Tuesday" },
	{ "question": "無くす", "answers": [ "なくす" ], "comment": "to lose something\nto get rid of" },
	{ "question": "熱い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "hot (thing)\npassionate (feelings, etc.); ardent; hot (e.g. gaze)\nhot (e.g. temper)\nzealous; enthusiastic; fired up\nintense; severe; extreme\nhot (topic); of interest" },
	{ "question": "父", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "father" },
	{ "question": "牛乳", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "(cow's) milk" },
	{ "question": "牛肉", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにく" ], "comment": "beef" },
	{ "question": "物", "answers": [ "もの", "ぶつ" ], "comment": "thing; object; article; stuff; substance\none's things; possessions; property; belongings\nthings; something; anything; everything; nothing\nquality\nreason; the way of things\nused to emphasize emotion, judgment, etc.; used to indicate a common occurrence in the past (after a verb in past tense); used to indicate a general tendency; used to indicate something that should happen\nitem classified as ...; item related to ...; work of ...\ncause of ...; cause for ...\nsomehow; somewhat; for some reason\nreally; truly\nstock; products\nstolen goods; loot; spoils" },
	{ "question": "犬", "answers": [ "いぬ" ], "comment": "dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)\nsnoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)\nloser; asshole\ncounterfeit; inferior; useless; wasteful" },
	{ "question": "猫", "answers": [ "ねこ" ], "comment": "cat\nshamisen\ngeisha\nwheelbarrow\nclay bed-warmer\nbottom; submissive partner of a homosexual relationship\ncat" },
	{ "question": "甘い", "answers": [ "あまい" ], "comment": "sweet-tasting; sweet; sugary; sugared\nfragrant (smelling); sweet (music)\nlightly salted; light in salt; not spicy\nnaive; overly optimistic; soft on; generous; indulgent; easy-going; lenient\nhalf-hearted; not finished properly\ninsufficient; not satisfactory; inadequate; loose\nmild\ntempting; enticing; luring\nskillful; skilful; clever; expert; wise; successful\ndelicious; appetizing; appetising; tasty\nfortunate; splendid; promising" },
	{ "question": "生きる", "answers": [ "いきる" ], "comment": "to live; to exist\nto make a living; to subsist\nto be in effect; to be in use; to function\nto come to life; to be enlivened\nto be safe (in baseball, go, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "生まれる", "answers": [ "うまれる" ], "comment": "to be born" },
	{ "question": "生徒", "answers": [ "せいと" ], "comment": "pupil" },
	{ "question": "男", "answers": [ "おとこ" ], "comment": "man; male\nfellow; guy; chap; bloke\nmale lover; boyfriend; man\nmanliness; manly honor; manly honour; manly reputation\nman; boy\nmale; man\nhusband\nson" },
	{ "question": "男の子", "answers": [ "おとこのこ" ], "comment": "boy; male child; baby boy\nman; boy" },
	{ "question": "町", "answers": [ "まち" ], "comment": "town; block; neighbourhood; neighborhood\nstreet; road\n109.09 m\n0.99 hectares" },
	{ "question": "留学生", "answers": [ "りゅうがくせい" ], "comment": "overseas student; exchange student" },
	{ "question": "番号", "answers": [ "ばんごう" ], "comment": "number; series of digits" },
	{ "question": "疲れる", "answers": [ "つかれる" ], "comment": "to get tired; to tire\nto be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)\nto starve" },
	{ "question": "病気", "answers": [ "びょうき" ], "comment": "illness; disease; sickness" },
	{ "question": "病院", "answers": [ "びょういん" ], "comment": "hospital" },
	{ "question": "痛い", "answers": [ "いたい" ], "comment": "painful; sore\nexceeding" },
	{ "question": "登る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "白", "answers": [ "しろ", "しら" ], "comment": "white\ninnocence; innocent person\nblank space" },
	{ "question": "白い", "answers": [ "しろい" ], "comment": "white" },
	{ "question": "百", "answers": [ "ひゃく" ], "comment": "100; hundred" },
	{ "question": "皆さん", "answers": [ "みなさん" ], "comment": "all; everyone; everybody" },
	{ "question": "目", "answers": [ "め", "もく" ], "comment": "eye; eyeball\neyesight; sight; vision\nlook; stare; glance\nan experience\nviewpoint\nstitch; texture; weave\nordinal number suffix\nsomewhat; -ish\norder\nitem (of a budget revision, etc.)\ncounter for go pieces; counter for surrounded positions (in go)" },
	{ "question": "着く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to arrive at; to reach\nto sit on; to sit at (e.g. the table)\nto put on (or wear) lower-body clothing (i.e. pants, skirt, etc.); to put on (or wear) footwear\nto affix a sword to one's hip\nto affix a bowstring to a bow" },
	{ "question": "着る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down); to put on\nto bear (guilt, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "知る", "answers": [ "しる" ], "comment": "to be aware of; to know; to be conscious of; to cognize; to cognise\nto notice; to feel\nto understand; to comprehend; to grasp\nto remember; to be acquainted with (a procedure)\nto experience; to go through; to learn\nto be acquainted with (a person); to get to know\nto concern" },
	{ "question": "私", "answers": [ "わたし", "わたくし" ], "comment": "I; me" },
	{ "question": "空", "answers": [ "そら", "から", "くう" ], "comment": "emptiness; vacuum; blank\nsky; the air; the heavens\nweather\nfar-off place; distant place\nstate of mind; feeling\n(from) memory; (by) heart\nfalsehood; lie\nsomehow; vaguely\nfake\nhollow; cavity; hole\nempty air; sky\nshunyata; emptiness; the lack of an immutable intrinsic nature within any phenomenon\nair force\nfruitlessness; meaninglessness\nvoid (one of the five elements)\nempty (e.g. set)" },
	{ "question": "窓", "answers": [ "まど" ], "comment": "window" },
	{ "question": "立つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to stand; to rise; to stand up\nto find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)\nto depart (on a plane, train, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "答える", "answers": [ "こたえる" ], "comment": "to answer; to reply" },
	{ "question": "箱", "answers": [ "はこ" ], "comment": "box; case; chest; package; pack; crate\ncar (of a train, etc.)\nshamisen case; shamisen\npublic building; community building\nman who carries a geisha's shamisen\nreceptacle for human waste; feces (faeces)\ncounter for boxes (or boxed objects)" },
	{ "question": "紅茶", "answers": [ "こうちゃ" ], "comment": "black tea" },
	{ "question": "紙", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "paper\nnewspaper" },
	{ "question": "細い", "answers": [ "ほそい" ], "comment": "thin; slender; fine\nunlucky (billiards slang)\nsmall; fine; minute\nstingy; cheap" },
	{ "question": "終わる", "answers": [ "おわる" ], "comment": "to finish; to end; to close" },
	{ "question": "結婚", "answers": [ "けっこん" ], "comment": "marriage" },
	{ "question": "結構", "answers": [ "けっこう" ], "comment": "splendid; nice; wonderful; delicious; sweet\nsufficient; fine (in the sense of \"I'm fine\"); (by implication) no thank you\nwell enough; OK; tolerable\nquite; reasonably; fairly; tolerably\nconstruction; architecture" },
	{ "question": "絵", "answers": [ "え" ], "comment": "picture; drawing; painting; sketch" },
	{ "question": "練習", "answers": [ "れんしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising" },
	{ "question": "置く", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "to put; to place\nto leave (behind)\nto establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.); to set up\nto appoint (someone to a certain position); to hire; to employ\nto place (one's trust, one's faith, etc); to bear (in mind etc)\nto put down a tool (e.g. a pen) hence stopping what one is doing with that tool\nto take in (boarders, etc.); to provide lodging in one's house\nto separate spatially or temporally\nto do something in advance\nto leave something in a certain state; to keep something in a certain state" },
	{ "question": "習う", "answers": [ "ならう" ], "comment": "to take lessons in; to be taught; to learn (from a teacher); to study (under a teacher); to get training in" },
	{ "question": "耳", "answers": [ "みみ" ], "comment": "ear\nhearing\nedge; crust\nselvedge (non-fray machined edge of fabrics); selvage" },
	{ "question": "聞く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "to hear\nto listen (e.g. to music)\nto ask; to enquire; to query\nto learn of; to hear about\nto follow (advice); to comply with\nto smell (esp. incense); to sample fragrance" },
	{ "question": "肉", "answers": [ "にく" ], "comment": "flesh\nmeat\nthe physical body (as opposed to the spirit)\nthickness\nink pad" },
	{ "question": "背", "answers": [ "せ", "せい" ], "comment": "height; stature\nback; spine\nreverse; rear side\nridge (of a mountain)" },
	{ "question": "背広", "answers": [ "せびろ" ], "comment": "business suit" },
	{ "question": "自分", "answers": [ "じぶん" ], "comment": "myself; yourself; oneself; himself; herself\nI; me\nyou" },
	{ "question": "自動車", "answers": [ "じどうしゃ" ], "comment": "automobile" },
	{ "question": "自転車", "answers": [ "じてんしゃ" ], "comment": "bicycle" },
	{ "question": "色", "answers": [ "いろ" ], "comment": "colour; color\ncomplexion\nappearance; look\nlove; lust; sensuality; love affair; lover\nkind; type; variety\ncounter for colours\nrupa (form)\nvisible objects (i.e. color and form)" },
	{ "question": "花", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "flower; blossom; bloom; petal\ncherry blossom\nbeauty\nblooming (esp. of cherry blossoms)\nikebana\nJapanese playing cards\n(the) best" },
	{ "question": "花瓶", "answers": [ "かびん" ], "comment": "(flower) vase\nvase used to hold flower offerings (often made of gilded copper)" },
	{ "question": "若い", "answers": [ "わかい" ], "comment": "young; youthful\nimmature; green\nlow (number); small" },
	{ "question": "英語", "answers": [ "えいご" ], "comment": "English (language)" },
	{ "question": "茶色", "answers": [ "ちゃいろ" ], "comment": "light brown; tawny" },
	{ "question": "荷物", "answers": [ "にもつ" ], "comment": "luggage; baggage; package\nburden\npayload (of a packet, cell, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "葉書", "answers": [ "はがき" ], "comment": "postcard\nmemo; note; card" },
	{ "question": "薬", "answers": [ "くすり" ], "comment": "medicine; pharmaceuticals; (legal) drugs; pill; ointment; salve\nefficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)\n(pottery) glaze\nsmall bribe\ndope; narcotics; drugs\nmedication; drug; treatment; anti-" },
	{ "question": "行く", "answers": [ "いく", "ゆく" ], "comment": "to go; to move (in a direction or towards a specific location); to head (towards); to be transported (towards); to reach\nto proceed; to take place\nto pass through; to come and go\nto walk\nto do (in a specific way)\nto stream; to flow\nto continue\nto have an orgasm; to come; to cum\nto trip; to get high; to have a drug-induced hallucination" },
	{ "question": "西", "answers": [ "にし" ], "comment": "west\nSpain" },
	{ "question": "見える", "answers": [ "みえる" ], "comment": "to be seen; to be in sight\nto look; to seem; to appear\nto come\nto have an audience; to meet; to see\nto face (an enemy); to confront\nto serve (esp. as one's wife)" },
	{ "question": "見せる", "answers": [ "みせる" ], "comment": "to show; to display" },
	{ "question": "見る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "to see; to look; to watch; to view; to observe\nto look over; to look on; to assess; to examine; to judge\nto look after; to keep an eye on; to take care of\nto view (e.g. flowers, movie)\nto try; to try out; to test\nto see that...; to find that..." },
	{ "question": "覚える", "answers": [ "おぼえる" ], "comment": "to memorize; to memorise; to commit to memory; to learn by heart; to bear in mind; to remember\nto learn; to pick up; to acquire\nto feel\nto think; to regard" },
	{ "question": "言う", "answers": [ "いう", "ゆう" ], "comment": "to say; to utter; to declare\nto name; to call\nto go (e.g. \"the alarm went ping\"); to make a noise" },
	{ "question": "言葉", "answers": [ "ことば" ], "comment": "language; dialect\nword; words; phrase; term; expression; remark\nspeech; (manner of) speaking" },
	{ "question": "話", "answers": [ "はなし" ], "comment": "talk; speech; chat; story; conversation\ndiscussions; negotiation; argument\ncounter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc." },
	{ "question": "話す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "to talk; to speak; to converse; to chat\nto tell; to explain; to narrate; to mention; to describe; to discuss\nto speak (a language)" },
	{ "question": "誕生日", "answers": [ "たんじょうび" ], "comment": "birthday" },
	{ "question": "読む", "answers": [ "よむ" ], "comment": "to read\nto count\nto guess; to predict; to read (someone's thoughts); to see (e.g. into someone's heart); to divine" },
	{ "question": "警官", "answers": [ "けいかん" ], "comment": "police officer; policeman; constable" },
	{ "question": "財布", "answers": [ "さいふ" ], "comment": "purse; handbag; wallet" },
	{ "question": "買い物", "answers": [ "かいもの" ], "comment": "shopping; purchased goods" },
	{ "question": "買う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "to buy; to purchase\nto value; to have a high opinion\nto stir; to provoke" },
	{ "question": "貸す", "answers": [ "かす" ], "comment": "to lend; to loan\nto rent out; to hire out" },
	{ "question": "質問", "answers": [ "しつもん" ], "comment": "question; inquiry; enquiry" },
	{ "question": "赤ちゃん", "answers": [ "あかちゃん" ], "comment": "baby; infant" },
	{ "question": "走る", "answers": [ "はしる" ], "comment": "to run\nto travel (movement of vehicles); to drive\nto hurry to\nto retreat (from battle); to take flight\nto run away from home\nto elope\nto tend heavily toward\nto flash; to streak; to shoot through (e.g. pain)" },
	{ "question": "起きる", "answers": [ "おきる" ], "comment": "to get up; to rise; to blaze up (fire)\nto wake up; to be awake; to stay awake\nto occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents); to happen; to take place" },
	{ "question": "車", "answers": [ "くるま" ], "comment": "car; automobile; vehicle\nwheel\ncar; vehicle" },
	{ "question": "辞書", "answers": [ "じしょ" ], "comment": "dictionary; lexicon\nletter of resignation" },
	{ "question": "近い", "answers": [ "ちかい" ], "comment": "near; close; short (distance)\nclose (in time); soon\nclose (relationship); friendly; intimate\nclosely related\nsimilar; likeworthy; almost the same" },
	{ "question": "近く", "answers": [ "ちかく" ], "comment": "near; neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity\nnearly (e.g. \"it took nearly one year\"); close to\nshortly; soon" },
	{ "question": "返す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "to return (something); to restore; to put back\nto turn over; to turn upside down; to overturn\nto pay back; to retaliate; to reciprocate\nto repeat ...; to do ... back" },
	{ "question": "速い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; hasty; brisk\nearly (in the day, etc.); premature\n(too) soon; not yet; (too) early\neasy; simple; quick" },
	{ "question": "遅い", "answers": [ "おそい" ], "comment": "slow\nlate (e.g. \"late at night\")\ntoo late\ndull; stupid" },
	{ "question": "道", "answers": [ "みち" ], "comment": "road; street; way; path; course; route; lane\ndistance; ways (e.g. \"a long ways\")\nthe way (of proper conduct, etc.); one's way; morals\nteachings (esp. Confucian or Buddhist); dogma\nfield (of medicine, etc.); subject\nway; method; means" },
	{ "question": "違う", "answers": [ "ちがう" ], "comment": "to differ (from); to vary\nto not be in the usual condition\nto not match the correct (answer, etc.)\nto be different from promised\nisn't it?; wasn't it?\nto differ; to be different\nto run counter to\nto change (into something out of the ordinary)" },
	{ "question": "遠い", "answers": [ "とおい" ], "comment": "far; distant" },
	{ "question": "部屋", "answers": [ "へや" ], "comment": "room; chamber\napartment; flat; pad\nstable" },
	{ "question": "重い", "answers": [ "おもい" ], "comment": "heavy; weighty; massive\nheavy (feeling); depressed; gloomy; blue; uneasy\nslow; sluggish; lumbering; ponderous; clumsy\nimportant; serious; grave\nserious; severe; critical\nsolid; established; dignified; sensible" },
	{ "question": "金曜日", "answers": [ "きんようび" ], "comment": "Friday" },
	{ "question": "銀行", "answers": [ "ぎんこう" ], "comment": "bank" },
	{ "question": "長い", "answers": [ "ながい" ], "comment": "long (distance)\nlong (time); lengthy" },
	{ "question": "門", "answers": [ "かど", "もん" ], "comment": "shutter; window shutter\nentrance (to a home)\nnarrows\ngate\nbranch of learning based on the teachings of a single master\ndivision; phylum\ncounter for cannons" },
	{ "question": "閉まる", "answers": [ "しまる" ], "comment": "to be shut; to close; to be closed\nto be locked\nto tighten; to be tightened\nto become sober; to become tense" },
	{ "question": "閉める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to close; to shut" },
	{ "question": "間", "answers": [ "あいだ", "ま", "かん" ], "comment": "space (between); gap; interval; distance\ntime (between); pause; break\nspan (temporal or spatial); stretch; period (while)\nrelationship (between, among)\nmembers (within, among)\ndue to; because of\ntime; pause\nspace\nroom\ninterval; space; interstice; threshold\nvalley; gorge; ravine\nloophole (in a wall); crenel; eyelet\ninterval; period of time\namong; between; inter-\n1.818 m (6 shaku)\ncounter used to number the gaps between pillars" },
	{ "question": "階段", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "stairs; stairway; staircase" },
	{ "question": "難しい", "answers": [ "むずかしい" ], "comment": "difficult; hard; troublesome; complicated; serious (disease, problem, etc.)\nfussy; particular; fastidious; hard to please; displeased\ngloomy; glum; sullen; serious (look)\ndirty; unclean; filthy; detestable\nunpleasant; uncomfortable; creepy; spooky" },
	{ "question": "雨", "answers": [ "あめ" ], "comment": "rain" },
	{ "question": "雪", "answers": [ "ゆき" ], "comment": "snow" },
	{ "question": "電気", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electricity\n(electric) light" },
	{ "question": "電話", "answers": [ "でんわ" ], "comment": "telephone call; phone call\ntelephone (device); phone" },
	{ "question": "電車", "answers": [ "でんしゃ" ], "comment": "train; electric train" },
	{ "question": "静か", "answers": [ "しずか" ], "comment": "quiet; silent\nslow; unhurried\ncalm; peaceful" },
	{ "question": "音楽", "answers": [ "おんがく" ], "comment": "music; musical movement" },
	{ "question": "頭", "answers": [ "あたま", "かしら", "ず" ], "comment": "head\nhair (on one's head)\nmind; brains; intellect\nleader; chief; boss; captain\ntop; tip\nbeginning; start\nhead; person\ntop structural component of a kanji\ntop of ..; head of ..\nthe moment that .." },
	{ "question": "頼む", "answers": [ "たのむ" ], "comment": "to request; to beg; to ask\nto call; to order; to reserve\nto entrust to\nto rely on" },
	{ "question": "風", "answers": [ "かぜ", "ふう" ], "comment": "wind; breeze; draught; draft\nmanner; behaviour; behavior\ncold; influenza\nmethod; manner; way; style\nappearance; air\ntendency\nfolk song (genre of the Shi Jing)\nwind (one of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "飛ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "to fly; to soar\nto jump; to leap; to spring; to bound; to hop" },
	{ "question": "飛行機", "answers": [ "ひこうき" ], "comment": "aeroplane; airplane; aircraft" },
	{ "question": "食べる", "answers": [ "たべる" ], "comment": "to eat\nto live on (e.g. a salary); to live off; to subsist on" },
	{ "question": "食べ物", "answers": [ "たべもの" ], "comment": "food" },
	{ "question": "食堂", "answers": [ "しょくどう" ], "comment": "dining room; dining hall; cafeteria; messroom\nrestaurant; eatery; snack bar; diner\ndining hall (at a temple)" },
	{ "question": "飲み物", "answers": [ "のみもの" ], "comment": "drink; beverage" },
	{ "question": "飲む", "answers": [ "のむ" ], "comment": "to drink; to gulp; to swallow; to take (medicine)\nto smoke (tobacco)\nto engulf; to overwhelm\nto keep down; to suppress\nto accept (e.g. demand, condition)\nto make light of; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "駅", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "station" },
	{ "question": "高い", "answers": [ "たかい" ], "comment": "high; tall\nexpensive" },
	{ "question": "魚", "answers": [ "さかな", "うお" ], "comment": "fish" },
	{ "question": "鳥", "answers": [ "とり" ], "comment": "bird\nbird meat (esp. chicken meat); fowl; poultry" },
	{ "question": "鳴く", "answers": [ "なく" ], "comment": "to sing (bird)\nto make sound (animal); to call; to cry; to chirp\nto make a meld call (e.g. pung, kong)" },
	{ "question": "黒", "answers": [ "くろ" ], "comment": "black\nblack go stone\nguilt; guilty person" },
	{ "question": "黒い", "answers": [ "くろい" ], "comment": "black\ndark\nillicit; wicked; underground" },
	{ "question": "薄い", "answers": [ "うすい" ], "comment": "thin\npale; light\nwatery; dilute; sparse\nweak (taste, etc.)\nslim (probability, etc.); small" }
]
}
